Entente Alliance, Port Arnelus
Please understand, Mary.
（アンソン）
分かってくれ メアリー
It's only a matter of time until
the war reaches the cities.
都市部にまで戦火が及ぶのも
時間の問題だ
It's safer for you to leave
the country while you can.
今のうちに
国外へ避難したほうがいい
What about you, Dad?
（メアリー）お父さんは？
（アンソン）すまん
I'm sorry.
私は いい父親ではなかったな
I wasn't a good father, was I?
No, you're a good dad.
ううん いいお父さんだよ
あっ でも おヒゲはそって
Oh, but you should shave your beard.
Yeah, I should.
ああ そうだな
Mary, take care of your mother.
メアリー
お母さんを助けてあげなさい
体には気をつけるんだぞ
And stay healthy.
Okay.
すまないな
I'm sorry.
Good luck, sir.
（アンソンの妻）ご武運を
（メアリー）お父さん！
Daddy!
It's a little early,
少し早いけど
クリスマスプレゼント大切にしてね
but take good care of your Christmas present!
（グンナー）スー大佐
Colonel Sioux...
Major Gunner.
（アンソン）グンナー少佐
This is from your daughter.
（グンナー）娘さんからです
What is this?
（アンソン）これは…
（グンナー）新型の短機関銃ですね
The latest model of submachine gun.
どうして娘が こんな物を…
Why would my daughter
give me something like this?
祖国のために戦う父親を支えたい…
そう思っていたのでは？
Perhaps she wants to help her father fight for his country?
"Anson Sioux."
“アンソン･スー”
Your initials, aren't they?
大佐殿のイニシャルですね
（ターニャ）故に 戦線を
意図的に後退させしめ―
Thus, we'll deliberately
pull back the battle lines
Imperial Army Northern Theater, Command Strategy Conference
北方軍における兵站(へいたん)の
距離的な負担を軽減
and reduce the distance supplies
must travel to the northern army.
結果として 春季以降の攻勢計画を
容易たらしめると確信します
I believe this will make it easier
for us to mount a spring offensive.
As always, the ideas front-line officers
come up with are quite unique.
（ルーデルドルフ）やはり
実際の現場で働く士官の提言は
なかなか斬新ですなあ
Well? What's the opinion of
the northern theater's army?
それで？
北方方面軍としての見解は
Major Degurechaff, was it?
デグレチャフ少佐… だったか
Yes, sir.
（ターニャ）はい
You seem to plan on
dragging this out beyond winter,
（シュライゼ）貴官は越冬を
想定しているようだが―
これ以上の長期戦は望ましくない
but we don't want the war to last any longer.
Our priority is to put an end to it
as quickly as possible.
早期解決こそが 当面の課題だ
しかし 攻勢に出たところで
物資が枯渇し
But if we do attack, we'll run out
of supplies almost immediately
程なく攻勢限界に直面します
and quickly reach the limits
of what we can do.
We're under no obligation to please
the enemy by wasting supplies and troops.
物資と兵員を浪費し
敵を喜ばせる義理もありません
At minimum, we have enough
for a three-week offensive!
少なくとも３週間の攻勢は可能だ
We just need to take out
their front-line forces.
正面戦力さえ撃破しえればよい
The interventions by the Republic
and the Allied Kingdom
共和国や連合王国の介入により
敵の抵抗は頑強です
have greatly strengthened enemy resistance.
I see no way we can take
them out in such a short time.
とても短期間で
打破しうるとは思えません
もうよい！
Enough!
I am obligated to register
my objections to this.
小官の義務として
断固異議を申し立てます
このままでは現場の部隊に
甚大な負担を及ぼすばかりかと
At this rate, I believe we'll just put
severe stress on our front lines.
そこまでだ！ 我々が現場を
軽視しているとでも言うつもりか！
That's enough out of you!
Are you saying we aren't concerned with
the lives of our troops on the ground?!
軽率な発言は控えたまえ！
Watch your mouth!
失礼しました
I'm sorry, sir.
西方では 友軍が泥をすすって
飢えに苦しんでおりましたが
Compared to when I was out west
and saw our soldiers starving,
ここ北方の司令部は 随分と
恵まれているようでしたので つい…
Northern Command here
seems to want something for nothing,
so I forgot myself.
（シュライゼ）き… 貴様！
そこまで言うなら西方に帰れ！
Y-You bitch!
Return to the western theater, then!
臆病者は無用だ！
We don't need cowards here!
Is that the consensus of the northern theater?
それが北方方面軍の
総意でありましょうか？
Shut up!
（シュライゼ）くどい！
（ターニャ）では…
All right.
Excuse me.
失礼いたします
うぐぅ…
Why won't you stop them?
（ターニャ）
なぜ お止めにならないのですか
With our present supply situation,
a full offensive is reckless.
現状での全面攻勢など無謀
破たんは目に見えておりますが
Its failure is obvious.
少佐 私は本音で話してほしい
Major, I want you to tell me
what you really think.
形式的な意見 具申の姿勢は
必要ない
Without the formalities of a proper proposal.
（ターニャ）
閣下 謹んで申し上げますが―
Sir, I humbly remind you that
I am a strategy officer.
小官は参謀将校です
I appreciate the request,
せっかくの
ご諮問ではありますが―
先達に対する形式的儀礼上
沈黙すべきと愚考いたしますが
but I believe that, out of courtesy
for my hosts, I must remain silent.
フッ なかなか辛辣(しんらつ)な意見表明だな
That's a rather acrimonious way
to express one's opinion.
Very well. I'll get to the point.
よろしい では本題に入ろう
If, hypothetically, the theater forces
were to proceed with their attack plan,
仮にだ 方面軍の言う攻勢計画を
遂行するとしたら―
what benefits would it bring?
どのような意味を見いだす？
（ターニャ）西方
ライン戦線の助攻としては
It would bring some benefits to
the western Rhine theater.
多少の意味を持つでしょう
It could blind the Republic to
our coming offensive against them.
共和国への攻撃準備が
ごまかせる可能性があります
If it went well, isn't it possible it could
reduce strain on the western front?
うまくすれば 西方の負担を
軽くすることも ありうるのでは？
お言葉ではありますが 厳しいかと
I'm sorry, sir, but I believe
that would be difficult.
I can't see the Republic sending
the north enough reinforcements
ライン戦線に影響するほどの増援を
共和国が送り込むとは思えません
to affect the Rhine front.
（ルーデルドルフ）うむ…
そのような観点からすると―
If you wish to look at things that way,
we should consider this full-out offensive
全面攻勢は あくまで―
協商連合に対する
陽動作戦と見るべきでしょう
nothing more than a decoy to
distract the Entente Alliance.
If we consider the
front-line offensive a decoy,
前線への攻勢を
陽動と見るならば―
その真意は 敵の後方を
抑えることにあるかと… んっ
its true benefit would be in
opening the rear to attack...
The rear?
後方？
後方… 後ろ？ 背後…
The rear...
Behind.
Back?
What's wrong, Major?
どうしたのかね 少佐
つまり 今回の攻勢計画は
So the goal of this offensive is to
create a diversion for our
troops to land from sea?
上陸のための かく乱が目的？
Where did you hear that?
（レルゲン）どこで耳にした
はっ… 何がでしょうか？
Hear what?
上陸作戦のことだ
ゼートゥーア閣下から聞いたのか！
About the landing!
Did General Zettour tell you?
I can't believe it.
信じられん…
Well, that's a surprise.
（ルーデルドルフ）驚きだな
一部の将校しか知らない作戦を
言い当てるとは
You guessed a plan that only
a few officers know about.
I simply realized that it would be
an effective plan under these circumstances.
目下の情勢から 一案として
有効だと判断したまでであります
ふむ… やはり貴様を
使うことにしよう
Then we'll use you, after all.
The 203rd Mage Battalion will go in
advance of the rest of the landing force.
二〇三大隊は 上陸作戦に先立ち
全軍の先鋒(せんぽう)だ
Yes, sir. We'll do everything we can.
はっ！ 拝命いたしました
It goes without saying that, strategically,
this is close to a surprise attack.
（ルーデルドルフ）言うまでもなく
本作戦は戦略上の奇襲に近い
Thus, our landing point needs to be where
the enemy would never expect it.
よって 攻撃目標についても
敵の想定を超えた地域で
なければならん
Which means?
と言うと…
The Orse Fjord.
オース･フィヨルドだ
Episode Seven
The Battle of the Fjord
Entente Alliance, Orse Fjord
Quite a view, huh?
絶景だな
A narrow, labyrinthine fjord,
covered with capes and islands.
入り組んだ狭いフィヨルドに
多くの岬と島々
The cliffs are steep,
岸壁も高く 点在する20門の砲台で
どこからでも狙える
and twenty cannons in the area
let us attack from any direction.
No navy in the world could
pass through this sea.
列強国の いかなる艦隊だろうと
この海は破れまいよ
Truly a natural fortress, isn't it?
まさに天然の要塞ですね
Is there any real need for us to be here?
我々が防衛に当たる必要も
ないのでは？
とは言え 守備隊は必要だろう
It does need defenders, though.
I don't like the fact that only our battalion
was sent here as reinforcements.
増派されたのが
我々１個大隊のみとは
ちと気に入らん
しかたないでしょう
But it's understandable, really.
The Empire has launched
a winter offensive on the front lines.
前線では 帝国軍の冬季攻勢が
開始されたそうです
So the brass has their hands full?
上層部も手いっぱいというわけか
（部隊長）諸君！ 祖国のために
よくぞ立ち上がってくれた！
Men, you have my gratitude for
rising up to defend our homeland.
With the help of youth like you,
若き諸君らの力があれば
勝利は確実である！
our victory is assured!
You have already been promised honor.
既に栄誉は約束されている！
So I expect you to fight hard,
not fearing death!
死をも恐れぬ奮戦を期待する！
（学徒兵たち）はっ！
Yes, sir!
At this point, all our country can do
is ask its youngsters to die.
（アンソン）もはや我が国は―
若者に“死んでくれ”としか
言えぬ状況だ
That's exactly why we adults
have to keep fighting, too.
なればこそ―
大人の我々も
戦い続けねばなるまい
December, Unified Year 1924
I guess it's possible, huh?
（ターニャ）やれなくはない… か
Target point approaching.
（パイロット）目標地点接近
エンジンカット
滑空態勢に入ります
Cutting engine and preparing to glide.
Everyone, get ready to drop.
総員！ 降下用意だ！
（隊員たち）はっ！
Yes, ma'am!
繰り返しになるが
本作戦は奇襲性を重んじる
Again, this plan relies on surprise.
We have thirty minutes to capture the fjords.
フィヨルド制圧の
タイムリミットは30分だ
Second Lieutenant Serebryakov,
you're a back-up officer.
セレブリャコーフ少尉
貴様も予備指揮官だ
If you lose contact with me
and the first lieutenants,
私と各中尉のシグナルを
ロストした場合 撤退を指揮しろ
command the retreat.
The retreat?
（ヴィーシャ）
撤退… でありますか
私と中尉連中を
ロストする時点で
If the first lieutenants and I
go down, the mission's a failure.
作戦は失敗だろう
The rest of you can't beat enemies with
the kind of equipment that can take us out.
そこまで重装備の敵が
出てくれば 成算はない
まったく…
鉱山のカナリアの気分だな
Man, I feel like a canary in a coal mine.
Let's sing them a pretty song, then.
（ヴァイス）では せいぜい
可憐(かれん)に鳴いてみせるとしましょう
How does a canary sing, anyway?
（ケーニッヒ）
はて… どう鳴けばよいのやら
（ノイマン）
ピヨピヨですかねえ？
"Chirp, chirp," right?
I don't want to hear you guys sing.
貴様らの鳴き声など聞きたくもない
さっさと行動に備えろ
Get ready for work.
（ターニャ）さて 諸君
All right, troops,
it's time for us aerial mages
to do what we do best.
航空魔導師としての
本領を発揮する時だ
You're ready, right?
（ターニャ）準備はよいな！
（隊員たち）はっ！
Yes, ma'am!
Excellent.
よろしい… 降下！
Jump!
What's going on?
（アンソン）どういうことだ！
（通信兵）分かりません
I don't know.
For some reason, we've lost
contact with a patrol ship.
なぜか 哨戒船からの定時連絡が
途絶えておりまして…
Equipment trouble?
機材の故障か？
What about the other
ships on the patrol line?
哨戒ラインの 他の船はどうだ？
The same.
（通信兵）同じです
３隻とも反応がありません
None of the three are responding.
What?
何だと？
What was that?
今のは!?
次だ！ 急げ！
Next! Hurry!
Prepare artillery spell!
（ケーニッヒ）砲撃術式 用意！
撃てー！
Fire!
（協商連合兵士）ハァ… うう…
Enemy attack...
（協商連合兵士）敵襲… 敵襲！
Enemy attack!
Wh-Where did they come from?
どっ どこから現れた!?
They paradropped.
空挺(くうてい)降下だ
（グンナー）
クソッ とにかく出撃だ！
Damn it.
Let's get out there!
Coastal gun platforms are engaged.
（協商連合兵士）
湾岸部の各砲台が交戦中！
They're requesting reinforcements.
（グンナー）増援の要請だ！
すぐに鉄道で送らせろ！
Get them out there via rail!
Why are they only attacking
the cannon emplacements?
なぜ砲台だけを…
Battalion Commander,
enemy reinforcements!
（ヴィーシャ）
大隊長！ 敵の増援です！
大隊規模の魔導部隊が
急速接近中！
Battalion-sized unit of
mages is approaching fast!
They responded fast.
対応が早いな
第１中隊！ 迎撃準備だ！
Company 1, prepare to engage!
（ヴァイス）少佐殿！
１個中隊では危険すぎます！
Major, engaging with a single
company is too dangerous.
こちらはこちらで 何とかする！
We can handle it!
貴様は さっさと砲台を黙らせろ！
You silence those damn guns!
う… 了解です！
Roger!
Company 1, follow me.
（ターニャ）第１中隊 続け！
（ターニャ）気乗りはしないが―
I don't like it,
部下がやられて
敵に頭を抑えられるよりはマシだ
but it's better than having them
take out my troops and trap me.
（協商連合魔導師）
迎撃 上がってきます！
Incoming counterattack.
The enemy is company-sized.
敵 およそ中隊規模！
Company-sized?
中隊規模だと？
ケッ なめられたものですね！
They don't see us as a threat, huh?
We're heading in.
Prepare for close-range combat!
切り込むぞ！ 接近戦だ！
（レルゲン）既に北洋艦隊は 敵の
哨戒ラインを越えたはずですが―
By now, the North Sea Fleet should have
crossed the enemy patrol line.
If those gun emplacements can't be
taken out in thirty minutes,
もし 30分で
砲台を制圧できなければ―
the fleet will have to turn back.
艦隊は引き返すしか…
If that happens, we'll have performed
the largest, most spectacular
（ルーデルドルフ）
その場合は 極めて実戦的な―
史上最大の上陸演習作戦だな
"landing training exercise"
in the history of man.
And our reputation will be ruined.
我々の面目も丸つぶれだ
頭を抑えろ！
Trap them!
頭を抑えられるな！
Don't let them trap you!
高度を落とすな！ 蹴散らせ！
Maintain altitude! Take them out!
Do they have those guns down yet?
（ターニャ）
砲台の無力化は まだか！
（ヴァイス）残りは！
（グランツ）まだです！
Are we done?
Not yet.
（協商連合兵士）
来たぞ！ 撃てー！
They're here!
Fire!
Enemy mages sighted.
（グランツ）敵魔導師を確認！
このままでは時間が…
We're running out of time.
Just keep firing.
とにかく撃て！ 手を動かせ！
Don't stop for a second!
Multiple casualties! We're being pushed back!
脱落者 多数！ 押されています！
Hang in there till reinforcements arrive!
増援が来るまで持ちこたえろ！
しかし！ このまま…
But at this rate—
グンナー少佐！
Major Gunner!
I'm dying from overwork here.
オーバーワークも甚だしいが
But I can't bail just because
this wasn't in the contract.
契約が違うと
飛び去るわけにもいかんしなあ
（アンソン）神よ…
God...
Why?
なぜですか…
Why... Why is she here?
なぜ… なぜ ヤツがここに!?
うおぉー！
邪魔だ！
Out of my way!
ハァ…
If I run, there goes my career...
逃げたらキャリアが消えるしなあ
What?
（アンソン）何!?
（ターニャ）すばらしい！
Wonderful.
No overtime today.
定時帰宅だ
（ヴァイス）繰り返す
I repeat.
All companies have succeeded
in silencing the guns!
各中隊 砲台の無力化に成功！
Reporting!
（大隊長）状況を通達！
現在 友軍の守備隊は劣勢！
Our defensive forces are losing the battle!
至急 沿岸部に向かい
支援任務に当たる
We will head to the coast
and aid the defense.
よって…
（爆撃音）
Thus—
任務は終了だ！ 総員撤収！
Mission complete.
Everyone, withdraw!
く… くうぅ…
まだだ！
Not yet.
It isn't over yet!
まだ終われはしない！
Enemy pursuit.
追撃です！ １体 来ます！
One mage incoming.
Damned fanatical patriots!
チッ 狂信的な愛国者め！
With that speed, he has a lot
of kinetic energy built up.
あの速度なら
相当な運動エネルギーだな
Oh, Lord,
主よ 父と子の名の下に
裁きの雷(いかずち)を落としたまえ
in the Father and Son's name,
bring down the lightning of judgment.
神よ 願わくば―
God, I pray you give me
strength to destroy that devil!
我に あの悪魔を
討ち滅ぼす力を与えたまえ！
祖国よ！
なんじを決して 滅ぼすものか！
I will never let my homeland fall!
ぐえっ… ぐああっ
ん？ この顔はどこかで…
I've seen you somewhere before.
ハァ… うっ… あ…
フゥ… まあ いいか
Not that it matters.
メ… メアリー…
M-Mary...
フゥ… ん？
ふむ 少し早いが
It's a little early,
自分へのクリスマスプレゼントに
ちょうどいいな
but this will make a perfect
Christmas present to myself.
（隊長）
鉄道を押さえろー！ 物資もだ！
Capture the railroads!
And the supplies!
（隊員たち）かんぱ～い！
Cheers!
絶景だな
Quite a sight, huh?
It's not over yet.
（カゾール）まだ…
まだ敗北が確定したわけでは…
Our defeat isn't set in stone yet.
The North Sea Fleet's
landing mission has succeeded.
（レルゲン）
北洋艦隊は揚陸に成功
既に オース市の鉄道を
制圧したそうです
Orse City railroads are under our control.
Now, we can use the enemy's
railways to resupply ourselves.
これで敵の鉄道を使って
物資の補給もできる
Bold as ever...
（ゼートゥーア）
相変わらず大胆なことだ
So you kicked the enemy's
ass from behind, huh?
敵の尻を
後ろから蹴り飛ばすとはな
We can attack from both front and rear now.
今後は 前方と後方からの
挟撃も可能となる
We can end a battle that's lasted too long.
長引いていた
戦線の処理も確実だろう
少し気は早いが まさに―
It feels a bit early to say for certain,
“決定的な一撃”というわけだ
but we have landed a truly decisive blow.
Unified Year 1925 Unified States, State of Arkansas
And now, in world news,
an update on the Norden situation
from DC Broadcasting.
Last December,
the Empire ran a successful
landing operation at Orse Fjord,
in the Entente Alliance's northern region.
The coastal defense forces were wiped out,
and many casualties were incurred.
After occupying Orse City,
the Empire launched a large-scale
assault from the north and south,
which resulted in the de facto
occupation of the nation's capital.
It's believed to be only a matter of time
before the Entente Alliance surrenders.
The situation will continue
to be monitored.
Next Episode
Trial by Fire
（ラジオ音声）続いては世界情勢
ＤＣ放送発表
ノルデン地方の戦況報告です
昨年12月
帝国軍は協商連合北部―
オース･フィヨルドへの
上陸侵攻を決行
沿岸部の守備隊は壊滅し
多くの死傷者が出たもようです
オース市を制圧後は―
北部 南部からの
大規模攻勢により―
同国首都を 事実上の占領下に
おいたとのことです
協商連合の降伏が行われるのも
時間の問題と見られており―
今後も情勢が注目されています